Pete M. McCarthy

Contact Github & Website

Mobile: 07791 963443 www.github.com/petemmccarthy e-mail: pete.m.mccarthy@gmail.com www.petemmccarthy.com

Personal Profile

I'm a Front End Developer who likes to produce clean, maintainable code and fantastic user experiences utilising Agile methodologies.

Previously, I've worked with the EmberJS framework and more recently I've been learning and using React and Redux and have attended the ReactJS Academy training course.

I have Back End experience with Java and a proprietary language FEL mostly with manipulating/filtering data to construct JSON to be sent to, or updating data sent from a client.

I also have an Economics degree and worked in Banking before becoming a Developer.

Work Experience

Software Developer — Answerspace Ltd — Dec 2016 - Jun 2018

- Software Developer for a data visualisation/business intelligence start-up using JavaScript, d3.js and jQuery libraries on the Front End, Java and a proprietary language FEL on the Back End
- My role was to enhance the main user interface which consisted of an SVG node graph and corresponding master/detail table
- Code was tested using Cucumber for Java, SourceTree and Git used for version control, workflow and defects were managed using JIRA
- Designing and documenting proposed solutions for user requirements covering development, testing, potential risks and mitigation and implementation
- I undertook some QA testing work which involved writing and executing User Acceptance Tests and testing other developers bug fixes
- Analysing and enhancing customer data and performing demonstrations to ensure they could understand the benefits our software would provide them

Front End Developer (Contract) — British Gas Plc — May 2015 - Aug 2016

- Worked as part of a Scrum team rebuilding the British Gas Home Services digital journey in two week sprints
- My role was to bring UX designs to life using the EmberJS framework following the British Gas Style Guide
- As well as JavaScript and the EmberJS framework I used the jQuery library, Bootstrap 3, HTML and CSS
- Code was tested using Qunit unit tests for functions/methods, integration tests for components and acceptance tests for overall user journeys
- GitHub was used for version control. All code was subject to peer reviewed/merged pull requests

Software and Web Development course — Makers Academy — Jun 2014 - Sep 2014

 Highly selective full-time Web and Software Development course with a focus on learning Object Oriented Programming and Test Driven Development to produce clean, maintainable code

Structured Products Middle Office — Nomura Plc — Jul 2010 - Jun 2014

- Built out and managed the operational support function for the Re-Insurance Trading business
- Operational support for the Algorithmic Strategies trading desk and Nomura Alternative Investment Management (NAIM) in house Fund Managers
- Delivered project to migrate Fund Managers operational support offshore to India

Structured Interest Rate and Inflation Trade Support — Citigroup — Sep 2008 - Jul 2010

- Managed the operational risks for trades too bespoke for risk management systems
- Operational support for exotic rates and inflation trading desks
- Delivered project to migrate all exotic rates coupon calculations and settlement affirmations offshore

Interest Rate Swaps Trade Support — J P Morgan — Mar 2007 - Sep 2008

- Managed the flow of Interest Rate Swaps and Forward Rate Agreements from trading floor execution through to risk management and Back Office systems, ensuring risk and P&L is captured and in line with expectations
- Supervisor to a team of four Traders Assistants

FX and Derivatives Product Manager — Barclays Corporate Banking — Aug 2005 - Mar 2007

- Driving and supporting sales of a circa £200m per annum profit FX and Derivatives product set for UK Corporate clients
- Achievements included per annum incremental profit increase of £3.5m from management of pricing margins, £2.5m through the creation of a skewed margin and £600k through pricing matrix realignments

Service Support Manager — Barclays Corporate Banking — Jan 2004 - Aug 2005

 Worked as part of a central Sales and Service team supporting Corporate Banking sales teams with sales campaigns and externally conducted customer surveys

Education

- Software and Web Development, Makers Academy (Jun 2014 Sep 2014)
- B.A. Economics, University of Leicester (Sep 2000 Jul 2003)
- Mathematics & Economics Foundation Course, University of Leicester (Sep 1999 Jun 2000)

Interests - Cycling, climbing, skiing, outdoor pursuits and travel.